Guide to the Yale Journal of Criticism Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Journal of Criticism records
1986-2006
RU 1006
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2
82.6
The records consist of meeting agendas and minutes, correspondence, proposals, subject files, and computer files documenting the Yale Journal of Criticism.
Yale Journal of Criticism (Organization)
Whitney Humanities Center
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Whitney Humanities Center, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Journal of Criticism was founded in 1986 by junior members of Yale University faculty and sponsored by the Whitney Humanities Center.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of meeting agendas and minutes, correspondence, proposals, subject files, and computer files documenting the Yale Journal of Criticism.
Yale journal of criticism; Criticism -- United States -- History -- 20th Century; Born digital; Yale Journal of Criticism (Organization)
- Records, circa 1986-2006; Accession 2006-A-208
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2041
  - Issue Paperwork (not complete: info for some issues missing), circa 1987-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 29)
  - Board Meetings: agendas, minutes, 1991, 1997-2004 (Box 1, Folder 30 - 39)
  - Johns Hopkins University Press: contract, publicity, permissions, etc., 1994-2003 (Box 1, Folder 40 - 48)
  - Permissions, 1988-2003 (Box 1, Folder 49 - 51)
  - "Reading Spaces" summary, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Editor/Managing Editor materials, 1987-2002 (Box 2, Folder 53 - 59)
  - YJC origins, 1985-1998 (Box 2, Folder 60 - 66)
  - Publicity, 1988-2001 (Box 2, Folder 67 - 69)
  - Financial/Funding info, 1987-2006 (Box 3, Folder 70 - 75)
  - Publisher info, 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 76 - 77)
  - YJC award from Conference of Editors of Learned Journals, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Previous reader's reports, 2001-2002
    General note
    Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
  - 12.2, 1999-2001
  - 12.2 misc, 1999-2000
  - 13.1, 2000
  - 13.1 pocket epic-correspondence, 1999-2000
  - 13.2, 2000
  - 14.1 correspondence, 2000
  - 14.1 essays-backup, 2000
  - 14.1 in progress, 2000
  - 14.2 backup, 2000
  - 14.2 in progress, 2001
  - 15.1 Irish cinema, 2000-2002
  - 15.2, 2002
  - 16.1, 2003
  - 16.2, 2003
  - 17.1, 2003-2004
  - 17.2, 2004
  - 18.1, 2004
  - 18.2, 2005
  - 2000
  - 2001
  - 2002 m.e. search
  - Current files, 2002-2005
  - Jhup, 2000-2002
  - Letters sent, -2000
  - Letters and logs, 1997-1999
  - YJC board meeting, 1998-2000